Try accept most languages have a concept of a try accept block.
Let's say that in my rep old, I tried to make a integer out of the letter A.
I'm going to get a value error here.
You know, my phone's like, I have no idea what to do with this.
This is just bad input.
If I don't want my program to quit,
I notice in the rep old exceptions get thrown,
but we can continue working.
In your Python file as soon as an uncaught exception is thrown,
that ends your program.
So a little bit of a difference there.
This is a lot easier to use for testing, debugging, et cetera,
without completely losing all of your stay.
Okay, so let's say I get some user input.
If I want to catch this exception,
I would put the code in under a try block.
And then I would accept.
And I would pass in the name of the class of the specific type of error
that I want to catch.
Luckily for us, it's pretty easy.
Python just prints it out right here.
So I'm going to say accept on value error and print out no way.
That's not.
That's not a number.
What are you thinking?
User.
Okay.
So what's going to happen here?
Our user input is a.
We're going to try to make it.
And into your Python's going to fail.
What code is going to run?
Code in the accept block.
The code index of block.
And just to show you again, if I have a try here,
and I'm trying to make an int.
And I print out, I'm going to say, sorry, I'm going to quit that.
And I'm going to say my number is int of user input.
Print out, great number.
Good job.
What's that?
I said, you did it.
You did it.
Exactly.
And now I'm going to accept on my value error and say, what are you doing?
Okay.
So it's going to print out no way that's not a number.
But it's not going to print out great number.
Why?
Because we never got to this code.
An exception was thrown here at this line.
And we immediately jumped to the accept clause.
You can, your accept clause can have multiple exceptions given as a tuple,
parenthesis to tuple.
That code will run if any of those exceptions are thrown.
So let's say I have a dictionary, a simple dictionary.
And I have my user input.
I can say, you know, try, turning my user input into an int or, you know, if that works fine.
And actually, sorry, I'm going to say that my user input is the number two.
So just to be clear, our D has that in it.
Our user input is two.
So I'm going to try to turn our user input into a integer.
And I'm also going to try to get the value in the dictionary on key based on the user input.
Now I can say, accept and pass in a list of our rather tuple of exception clauses.
So we know type R is going to be one of them.
What's the other one?
How value error?
Oh, right, I'm sorry, value error.
And what's the other one?
What error do we get?
If we try to get a key from a dictionary, that's not correct.
That's not correct.
A key from a dictionary that's not correct.
Print.
Oh, no.
Okay.
So, oh, I'm so sorry, let's see.
Let me try that again.
So, into a user input, and I'm just going to print it out.
And I also wanted to get the dictionary, not a user by a user input.
And then the rest of this code will be the same, except value error here.
And then we're going to print, oh, no.
So this time, we will print the user input.
But then we're going to print, oh, no.
And this, sorry, this prints out twice because of the ripple here.
So this, through a cure, and this general except clause, caught both of them.
We can also stack or try an accepts.
Generally, we want to catch the more specific one first and the less specific one later.
And one more thing about except the except clause, we can also give that exception a name
if we want to do anything with it.
Look at the label, log it, whatever.
So I can say, you know, try to make an integer out of this.
And then accept on that value error.
And to give this a name, I can say, as e, or doesn't matter what you name it.
And then I can print out, oh, no, as well as e.
And that gives us the message for that exception.